Babak Alipoursaied, P.Eng.

Cell: +1(780) 884 4380

bpoursaied@yahoo.com

Senior I&C Engineer with + 20 years of experience.

Proven experience in various industries including pipelines, oil and gas, hydrocarbons, mining, refineries, petrochemicals, liquid natural gas plant, hydroelectric power plants and marine terminals and have a thorough understanding of engineering in design of instrumentation and control systems in multi-disciplinary projects, experienced in Technical Bid Evaluations (TBEs) of I&CS for mechanical and process packages, and experience in leading instrumentation teams in successfully completing projects to specific time schedules, completing SIL studies and preparing safety documents specifically F&G layouts and Cause and Effect charts, and prepared control philosophies and overall system architecture block diagrams.

Employment History

• Jan 2012 - Mar 2015

Senior Instrumentation and Automation Engineer Worley parsons Edmonton, Alberta Canada

SUNCOR, New HP Boiler Oil Refinery Project.

Responsible for developing Demolishing Engineering Work Package (EWP) and dealing with vendors.

AREVA, Mc Clean Lake, Saskatchewan, Canada - JEB Mill Upgrade uranium mine project.

Responsible for developing Engineering Work Packages (EWPs) and dealing with vendors for the areas: 320 leaching and Atmospheric, 330 Counter Current and Decantation, 335 Clarification, 397 Reagents, 376 tailing.

TransCanada- Keystone Pipeline Project.

Responsible as Completion Lead developed I&C engineering for the expansion TransCanada Keystone Pipeline project. The expansion is complementary to the first phase of the project and the scope included 38 pump stations and 61 remote block valve sites in approximate 3,200 kilometres using 36 inch crude oil pipeline.

SUNCOR, Fort McMurray, Alberta, Canada -Fort Hills Oil Sand Project.

Responsible for mechanical packages related to the extraction and tailings and common areas. Developed design of control valves in the extraction and tailing areas and prepared a TBE for 20", 30" and 48" knife gate valves. Analyzed the use of double block and bleed KGV.

Mar 2009 - Dec 2011

Senior Instrumentation and Controls Engineer -Mapna Co -Tehran, Iran SUNIR-Alsadr Simple Cycle Power Plant 2x162 MW (GE V94.2) Project.

Responsible for developing design philosophy in the form of I&Cs Engineering Design Guidelines. Prepared P&IDs, instrument index and datasheets. Developed specifications, Material Requisitions (MRs) and technical bids, prepared control system narratives and state diagrams.

Babak Alipoursaied, P.Eng.

Cell: +1(780) 884 4380

bpoursaied@yahoo.com

Nov 2007 - Feb 2009

Senior Instrumentation and Control Engineer *-Fluor Canada* Ltd -Calgary, Alberta Canada Valero Energy, Port Arthur, Texas / St. Charles, Louisiana US. Unified Hydro Cracker Units Project.

Responsible for developing P&IDs and cause and effect for mechanical packages. Prepared specifications for DCS, SIS, TMR and vibration monitoring systems. Developed TBEs for centrifugal / make-up compressors and implemented Smart Plant Instrumentation. Liaised with vendors as required.

Feb 2005 - Oct 2007

Senior Instrumentation and Controls Engineer -Petro-Ex Canada -Toronto, Ontario Canada Sirte Oil Company, Sirte, Libya - Miscellaneous Oil and Gas Projects.

Responsible for the preparation of Instrumentation and Controls technical requirements for MRs. Prepared conceptual designs and performed quality checks of detailed design packages. Prepared detailed switch over schedule, with termination data base and step by step procedure, consisting of two GE Gas Turbine driven water injection pumps and their auxiliaries using GEs SIMPLEX Gas Turbine Controls. Prepared ladder diagram program for the dehydrator sequencing application using Allen Bradley PLC-5 programming software for Allen-Bradley PLC-5/25 based systems.

Feb 2003 - Jan 2005

Senior Instrumentation and Control Engineer -Mobine Co. -Asaluyeh, Iran Pars Energy zone -Central Utility Plant Project.

I&C Responsible Engineer for above project at a Nitrogen plant (20,000 M3/Hr, Oxygen plant 160 T/H, Air Plant 14,000 M3/Hr). Developed FFB segment diagrams and PLC networks, Implemented Yokogawa Centum 3000 and distributed control systems, HIMA Sella shutdown system and fiber optic network, and Liaised with vendors.

• Sep 2000 - Jan 2003

Senior Instrumentation and Control Engineer -Farab Co. -Tehran, Iran Masjed Soleman, Iran - 4X250 MW Karun (1) Hydro Electric Power Plant Project.

Responsible for the preparation of the project Scope of Work. Developed P&IDs and specifications for DCS, ESD, and interfacing panels. Prepared MRs, TBEs and technical correspondence with vendors and client on technical queries and clarifications.

• Apr 1999 - Aug 2000

Instrumentation and Control Engineer -Antibiotic Sazi Iran Co. (ASICO) -Tehran, Iran Pharmaceutical Plant Project.

Developed alternate design control system as required. Reviewed technical bids and RFQs. Prepared detail design of instrumentation and control system with Siemens PCS 7., created installation detail drawings, completed control valve calculations, instrument index and wiring and instrument loop diagrams.

Babak Alipoursaied, P.Eng.

Cell: +1(780) 884 4380

bpoursaied@yahoo.com

• Dec 1996 - Mar 1999

Instrumentation and Control Engineer - Gol-e-Gohar Co. -Tehran, Iran Iron Ore Beneficiation Project (2.75 Million t/v of Fe Concentrate).

Developed loop diagrams, installation details, control room layout and ESD matrix. Prepared MRs for crasher, conveyor system, storage bin, vibrating feeder system, grinding ball mill, high frequency screen, magnetic separator, refined powder system and auxiliary systems.

Nov 1990 - Oct 1996

Instrumentation and Controls Engineer -HSCO -Bandar Abbass Terminal Project (7MT/Y).

The scope of this project included ship loader, bucket wheel reclaimers, bucket wheel stacker reclaimers multiconveyor and wagon loading / unloading systems.

Reviewed vendor drawings and documents, and developed P&IDs, wiring interconnection diagrams, instrument loop diagrams, and installation details and provided construction support to site contractors.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering Majoring in Control Systems, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, 1987

Registration

Association of Professional Engineers and Geoscientists of Alberta (APEGA)

Specific Technical Expertise courses

Specialist courses attended include:

Alberta Construction Safety Association Safety Training, 2012

ISA (Safety Integrity Level), Fluor, Calgary, Alberta, Canada, 2008

Smart Plant Instrumentation (SPI), Fluor, Calgary, Alberta, Canada, 2007

Allen-Bradley & Modicon Quantum Xincon Technology, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, 2005

Centum 3000 & YS-80 Series Instruments, Yokogawa, Tehran, Iran, 2000

Siemens PLC (Simatic S5 family), Siemens, Tehran, Iran, 1997

Moore DCS Configuration and Programming, Tamam Co., Tehran, Iran, 1999